MICHAEL KOLES

CREATIVE CODER / FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

Profile

I am a Creative Coder / Front-End Web Developer with a diverse background in computer science, economics and the arts.

I enjoy being creative and inquisitive, learning and building new things every day. I passion is to create innovative experiences and to tell stories using the latest technologies.

Tech Stack

Programming/Scripting Languages















JavaScript CSS

HTML TypeScript

Bash

Web Dev Frameworks, Libraries & More











Webpack





Software & Tools





















Linux Illustrator XD Photoshop Figma VSCode * Basic knowledge

Sample Projects

JavaScript Software Synthesizer 🕝 🕮

The JavaScript Software Synthesizer is a web application enabling you to make and play music in the browser. It is a software synthesizer utilizing the Web Audio API by implementing a variety of JavaScript libraries.

Technologies: Tone.js, JavaScript, Sass, npm

Particircle ()

A Circle of Particles.

Technologies: p5.js, JavaScript

3D Cube (7)

A 3D cube rotating according to mouse movement.

Technologies: p5.js, JavaScript Minesweeper Emoji

The classic game reimagined and implemented with emojis.

Technologies: p5.js, JavaScript Circle Random Lines 🗀 🌐

A circle created dynamically by random lines.

Technologies: p5.js, JavaScript

Scribble Text 🗀 🌐

Text gradually appears whilte scribbling.

Technologies: p5.js, JavaScript

Fractal Mountain (7)

A p5is recreation of the triangle that turns into a mountain. Technologies: p5.js, JavaScript

> The list comprises both bits that have been included to final products and personal side projects. A fuller list can be found in my personal web page.

Contact



michaelkolesidis.com/





michaelkolesidis in michaelkolesidis



michael.kolesidis@gmail.com



+306976941600 (Greece) +447365113313 (UK)

Education

University of Macedonia

MSc Applied Informatics (Ongoing) Thessaloniki, Greece

University of Macedonia

BSc Economics

Thessaloniki, Greece

Universitat de Barcelona

BSc Economics (Exchange Student) Barcelona, Spain

University of Sussex

BA (Hons) Drama: Theatre and Performance Brighton, United Kingdom

Certificates

Social Hackers Academy

Frontend Web Development Certificate

University of Sussex

General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

University of Sussex

Diversity in the Workplace

Experience

Freelancer

Front-End Web Developer

Feb 2022 - Present

Social Hackers Academy

Student Mentor

Mar 2022 - Present

Manning Publications

Live Project Beta Tester / Book Reviewer Nov 2021 - Present

Languages

Greek (Native)

English (Proficient | C2)

Spanish (Intermediate | B2)

German (Basic | B1)

